{
  "title": "General_Aptitude-_CSE - Verbal_Ability_–_CSE — Slot 7 (19 Questions)",
  "duration": 53,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Verbal_Ability_–_CSE — Slot 7",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Choose the grammatically INCORRECT sentence: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>He is of Asian origin.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>They belonged to Africa.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>She is an European.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>They migrated from India to Australia.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>She is an European.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1564/gate-cse-2013-question-60#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Were you a bird, you ______ in the sky. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>would fly</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>shall fly</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>should fly</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>shall have flown</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>would fly</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1563/gate-cse-2013-question-59#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Complete the sentence:\n<br><br>\nUniversalism is to particularism as diffuseness is to ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>specificity</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>neutrality</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>generality</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>adaptation</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>specificity</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1560/gate-cse-2013-question-57#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following options is the closest in meaning to the word given below?<br><br>\nNadir <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Highest</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Lowest</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Medium</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Integration</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Lowest</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1559/gate-cse-2013-question-56#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Wanted Temporary, Part-time persons for the post of Field Interviewer to conduct personal interviews to collect and collate economic data. Requirements: High School-pass, must be available for Day, Evening and Saturday work. Transportation paid, expenses reimbursed.\n<br><br>\nWhich one of the following is the best inference from the above advertisement? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Gender-discriminatory</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Xenophobic</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Not designed to make the post attractive</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Not gender-discriminatory</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Not gender-discriminatory</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2209/gate-cse-2012-question-61#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate alternative from the options given below to complete the following sentence:\n<br><br>\nSuresh's dog is the one ________ was hurt in the stampede. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>that</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>which</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>who</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>whom</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>that</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2200/gate-cse-2012-question-60#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Choose the grammatically INCORRECT sentence: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>They gave us the money back less the service charges of Three Hundred rupees.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>This country's expenditure is not less than that of Bangladesh.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The committee initially asked for a funding of Fifty Lakh rupees, but later settled for a lesser sum.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>This country's expenditure on educational reforms is very less.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>This country's expenditure on educational reforms is very less.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2198/gate-cse-2012-question-59#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following options is the closest in meaning to the word given below?\n<br><br>\nMitigate <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Diminish</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Divulge</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Dedicate</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Denote</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Diminish</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2197/gate-cse-2012-question-58#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate alternative from the options given below to complete the following sentence:\n<br><br>\nDespite several _________ the mission succeeded in its attempt to resolve the conflict. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>attempts</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>setbacks</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>meetings</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>delegations</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>setbacks</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2195/gate-cse-2012-question-57#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Few school curricula include a unit on how to deal with bereavement and grief, and\nyet all students at some point in their lives suffer from losses through death and parting.\n<br>\nBased on the above passage which topic would not be included in a unit on bereavement? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>how to write a letter of condolence</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>what emotional stages are passed through in the healing process</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>what the leading causes of death are</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>how to give support to a grieving friend</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>what the leading causes of death are</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2171/gate-cse-2011-question-61#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Choose the word from the options given below that is most nearly opposite in the meaning to the given word\n<br>\nAmalgamate <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>merge</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>split</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>collect</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>separate</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>separate</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2170/gate-cse-2011-question-60#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence.\n<br>\nIf you are trying to make a strong impression on your audience, you cannot do so by being understated, tentative or ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>hyperbolic</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>restrained</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>argumentative</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>indifferent</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>restrained</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2169/gate-cse-2011-question-59#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word(s) from the options given below to complete the following sentence.\n<br>\nI contemplated _________ Singapore for my vacation but decided against it. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>to visit</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>having to visit</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>visiting</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>for a visit</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>visiting</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2167/gate-cse-2011-question-58#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following options is the closest in the meaning to the word below:\n<br>\nInexplicable <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Incomprehensible</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Indelible</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Inextricable</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Infallible</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Incomprehensible</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2165/gate-cse-2011-question-56#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Modern warfare has changed from large scale clashes of armies to suppression of civilian populations. Chemical agents that do their work silently appear to be suited to such warfare; and regretfully, there exist people in military establishments who think that chemical agents are useful tools for their cause.\n<br><br>\nWhich of the following statements best sums up the meaning of the above passage: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Modern warfare has resulted in civil strife.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Chemical agents are useful in modern warfare.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Use of chemical agents in warfare would be undesirable.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>People in military establishments like to use chemical agents in war.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>People in military establishments like to use chemical agents in war.</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2371/gate-cse-2010-question-63#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": "<p>The question below consists of a pair of related words followed by four pairs of words. Select the pair that best expresses the relation in the original pair.\n<br>\nUnemployed : Worker <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>fallow : land</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>unaware : sleeper</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>wit : jester</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>renovated : house</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>fallow : land</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2368/gate-cse-2010-question-60#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence:\n<br>\nIf we manage to __________ our natural resources, we would leave a better planet for our children. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>uphold</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>restrain</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>cherish</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>conserve</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>conserve</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2366/gate-cse-2010-question-58#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following options is the closest in meaning to the word given below:\n<br>\nCircuitous <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>cyclic</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>indirect</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>confusing</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>crooked</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>indirect</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2365/gate-cse-2010-question-57#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence:\n<br>\nHis rather casual remarks on politics ________ his lack of seriousness about the subject. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>masked</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>belied</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>betrayed</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>suppressed</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>betrayed</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2364/gate-cse-2010-question-56#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}